Better call an ambulance.
最好叫辆救护车
- 5251, Chicago. - 5251.
- 5251号 芝加哥分局 - 5251收到
Better send an ambulance out to the Eisenhower...
叫一辆救护车来艾森豪威尔高速路
in front of the MacKenzie turnoff.
就在麦肯兹岔道前面
Got a wreck. We got coverage. We'll send it in with the bike man.
是车祸 我们已经拍到了 一会儿让摩托车送过去
- Ten-four. - Okay.
- 收到 - 好
5251, clear.
5251号就位
Now, that's his public posture, but he's the one who's right there...
那是他的公众形象 但同样正是他...
with his eyes glued to the screen when the blood starts running--
鲜血四溅的时候 他会变得目不转睛
And he's the one who says, "Ooh, isn't it horrible?.
还说 “噢 这真是太惨了”
Isn't it horrible?. Let me see some more."
“这真是太惨了啊 再给我多看点”
There are a lot of people who buy The New York Times.
但《纽约时报》有很多读者
What I mean to say is that it happens--
我的意思是...
It has happened always, whether it was a photographer...
这种事时有发生 不管是摄影师
or a journalist or a cameraman.
还是记者 还是摄像师
When you are in the middle of something happening, you--
当你身处事件发生当时
It is a risk of the profession.
是要冒职业风险的
What's the difference between a person who types something and a typewriter?.
打字的人和打字机本身有什么区别？
The typewriter doesn't really care about what's being typed.
打字机不在乎打出的内容
But a typewriter's a machine, and you're not a machine.
但打字机是机器 你又不是
Actually, I'm kind of an elongation of a tape recorder.
其实我是录音机的延伸体
I've made films on all kinds of social problems.
我的电影涉及各种社会问题
The big bombs were the ones where we went into detail...
其中最失败的几部 是我们...
and showed why something happened.
试图深入其中 展现问题发生的原因
Nobody wants to take the time. They'd rather see 30 seconds of somebody...
没人愿意浪费这个时间 他们情愿花个30秒
getting their skull cracked, turn off the TV and say, "Let me have a beer."
看别人被爆头 关掉电视说 “好惨啊 我再喝瓶啤酒吧”
But Hollywood, the news med--
但是好莱坞 和新闻媒体...
Well, our position is one to-- to record.
我们的任务是记录
The dynamics that are happening in society--
社会上正在发生的事情...
We don't deal with the static things.
我们不拍静止的东西
We deal with the violence. We deal with--
我们拍的是暴力
Who wants to see somebody sitting, to see somebody lying down...
谁想看别人坐在那里 或者躺在那里
somebody talking peace, unless they're talking loud?.
谁想看别人谈论和平？除非是很重要的讨论
The cameraman makes the choice himself.
我觉得摄像师是有选择权的
He's out to get the blood and guts.
正是他们本人拍下了这些血腥暴力的画面
I believe that. The other night on television...
我就是这么认为的 昨天晚上电视上
there was a fellow in Gary-- in the ghetto.
一个人 在加里市的贫民区...
If there's something else that maybe is nice, that could fill the news...
就算有别的事情值得做成新闻
he'll take the stabbing, even if he's had 27 minutes of stabbing before.
他还是会去拍捅人案 尽管之前已经有27分钟的捅人案新闻了
They're someplace safe, away from it. They deplore it...
他们在距事发地很远的安全之处 会对之表示谴责
but they deplore it like all good people.
但和其他所有好人一样 都在谴责
All good people deplore problems at a distance, like Thomas Jefferson.
所有的好人都是站在远处谴责的 比如托马斯·杰弗逊
He loved the common man, but at a distance.
他喜欢民众 但保持距离
This is exactly what happened.
事实就是如此
Five cameramen have been killed, one in Germany.
五名摄影记者遇害 其中一个在德国
He was beat to death by a mob, literally beat to death-- for UPI.
这位合众社的记者被暴徒活活打死
Know the excuse?. The crowd thought he was taking pictures for the police.
知道为什么吗？对方认为他是给警方拍照的
They had a couple of fellas in a civil rights protest...
民权抗议活动中 有两个人
that were chained together, and I was taking pictures.
被链条绑在一起 我当时在拍照
Cops said, "Don't you think you'd better load the camera?'
警察说 “你是不是应该给相机换胶卷了？”
I says, "I'm not out of film." They said, "Load it anyway.
我说 “这里面还有” 他们说 “你还是换吧”
We wanna move these guys." And he starts pushing the lens.
“我们要把这些人转移走” 然后他就开始推搡我的镜头
I says, "The next time you push me, I'll fall down and start crying."
我说 “你再这样推我 我就会倒在地上开始大叫”
He walked away.
他就走了
The 1 20 Angineaux lens, and yanking back and forth...
120安吉尼厄镜头来回拉动
yelling "Black Power" at me, and I'm just shaking to death...
他们大喊“黑色力量” 我吓得浑身发抖
with a $1,200 lens on the camera.
相机上挂着一千二百块的镜头呢
I am in the middle. I got no place to hide.
事件当时 我没处藏身
I'm carrying a 40-pound camera, trying to get pictures of it.
身上背着40磅重的照相机 试图用它拍摄
The rioterwants to beat me up, thinks I'm trying to identify him for police.
暴徒们想要打我 他们以为我要向警方指认
The policeman wants to elbow me out of the way...
警察也想把我挤开
and I'm being gentle about it because he doesn't want the sergeant to see...
我也很顺从 因为他也不想让长官看到
he picked up some guy by his neck and threw him in the backseat of a car.
他拽着别人的脖颈 将其扔到警车后座
Then the editor says, "I want the pictures.
然后编辑会说 “我只要照片”
My audience doesn't care what brought this on."
“观众们不在意事情的起因”
You have to feed your family. You need the money.
你也要养家糊口 需要拿工资
Ifyou don't bring them back, you're not going to have a job.
如果你不拍照片带回去 你就会失业
Forget that. I've got a job to do, and I'm interested in it.
暂不提这个 我有一份自己喜爱的工作
The point I resent very much is the fact that wherever I go, I'm beat up.
我愤慨的原因是 自己不管去哪 都会被打
Shoot into those troops!. Shoot 'em!
- 有军队 开枪！ - 开枪！
Shoot the shit out of'em! Get 'em!
开枪打死他们！
You guys are shot!
你们中枪了！
What kind of country is this?. What's wrong?.
这国家到底是怎么回事？
We're people! Why do you have soldiers here with bayonets?.
我们是平民！为什么让军队拿着刺刀对付我们？
We got a captive. Hold on.
发现一名俘虏 等等
That was an unprovoked attack that was retaliatory--
这次无端的袭击 是报复性的...
Not me. Not me.
不要拍我
This man has an obsolete weapon.
这人手里拿着过时的武器
Make love, not war.
要做爱 不要战争
They stabbed one of our guys in the belly.
有人肚子上被捅了一刀
I am Brigadier General Richard T. Dunn...
我是陆军准将理查德·T·邓恩
commanding general of the emergency operation headquarters...
伊利诺伊州陆军国民警卫队
of the Illinois Army National Guard.
紧急行动总部的司令官
The emergency operation headquarters...
紧急行动总部
is one which was established last winter...
成立于去年冬年
for the purpose ofplanning and controlling operations...
目的是 在骚乱事件中
in the event of civil disturbances.
进行策划和控制
Over.
完毕
Out in the street, their bayonets are fixed...
街道上 他们的刺刀已经准备好了
and they know it's for real in a real riot in the city.
他们知道这是真正的暴动 需要真正的镇压
And here we know it's more or less--
我们也可以看到
It's a war game, more or less.
这几乎是一场战争
How's it going so far?
目前事态如何？
I couldn't tellyou. I'm the enemy.
这我没法说 我支持敌方
We love you guys.
爱死你们了
We have women foryou, beer.
我们给你们准备了女人和啤酒
Come on!
前进！
- Sing it, now. - Glory, glory, hallelujah
- 现在一起唱 - #光荣 繁盛 哈利路亚#
His truth is marching on
#真理在前行#
- When do we want freedom? - Now!
- 什么时候需要自由？- 现在！
- When do we want equality?
- 什么时候需要平等？- 现在！
- When are we gonna get it? - Now!
- 什么时候可以实现？- 现在！
It is what our forefathers fought for-- the free choice ofpeople!
这是先辈们抗争过的 人民的自由选择权！
Y eah!
是！
This country is changing.
这个国家正在变化
It is no longer for all the people.
它不再为所有人服务
- It is for some ofthe people. - Y eah!
- 只是为了某些人 - 对！
- We see a war we do not want.
- 我们不愿看到这场战争 - 对！
We see an apathy towards love and brotherhood.
他们没有爱 和手足情谊
Y eah!
对！
- Bring out the mayor. - We want the mayor!
- 让市长出来 - 我们要见市长！
- Hold on.
- 等等 - 我们要见市长！
We want the mayor!
我们要见市长！
We'll bring thejudge out to talk to you.
我们会派法官来交涉
We want the mayor! We don't want a flunky!
我们只要市长！不要奴才！
My friends, I've stood before you many times.
朋友们 我们已经见过很多次了
Tell it to 'em, Mayor!
朝他们说啊 市长！
You elected me mayor ofthis town for the last 20 years.
过去20年 你们选我为本市的市长
- No, we didn 't! - Tell it to 'em!
- 我们没有！- 这么告诉他们啊！
We've given you everything that we thought you needed.
你们的需求 我们已经全部满足了
I've let you use our swimming pool every 4th ofJuly.
每年7月4日 允许你们使用游泳池
We want it every day ofthe year!
我们要求每天都用！
We've operated--
我们的...
We've operated the liquor store with a minimum ofprofit.
我们用最小的利润经营酒水店
Sock it to 'em, baby! Sock it to 'em.
给他们一次猛击！
I understand that you have some problems.
我知道你们还有一些问题
- You have avoided our problems! - I understand that you have--
- 你回避了我们的问题！- 我明白...
I understand that you have some complaints.
我明白你们有所抱怨
We shall overcome.
一起唱“我们要战胜一切”
We shall overcome
#我们要战胜一切#
Some day
#能战胜一切#
Get the guys with the cameras.
抓住摄影的人
Four, three, two, one.
四 三 二 一
Fade in. Richard starts back.
画面渐入 理查德 开始
And cue announce. And keep on coming.
插入新闻宣读 继续
- And hold. - What's wrong?
- 等一下 - 怎么了？
Now. Down and in slowly.
现在 慢慢推进
Very slowly.
要很慢地
You riding iris on this, Jerry, or what?
杰瑞 是你负责对焦吗？
Slate on one. Stand by to take.
一号机就位
Roll tape to record. In, Arnold.
阿诺德 开始录制
- Stand by. - Four, three...
- 准备 - 四 三...
two, one.
二 一
Fade in.
画面渐入
You want to move over here, please?.
麻烦移到这边来好吗？
Let's go. Time is money. Let's go.
快点 时间就是金钱
Gus, is the El too loud for you?.
盖斯 这个火车是不是太吵了？
No, we can live with it.
不会 可以接受
Who here is old enough to vote?.
你们之中谁到了选举年龄？
I took my physical last week.
我上星期刚做过体检
Physical to vote?.
选举体检？
- Why are you working for Kennedy?. - He's the best.
- 你为什么支持[罗伯特]肯尼迪？- 他是最好的
- He's got long hair. - He's against the war.
- 他是长发 - 他反战
- What are you doing here?. - She's my friend.
- 你在这里是做什么的？- 她是我的朋友
He's an idealist. He's for anyone who hasn't got a chance.
他是理想主义者 一心为了所有机会渺茫的人
- Who are you for?. - I don't like him because of Oswald...
- 你支持谁？- 我不喜欢他 因为...
and Dallas and all that.
奥斯沃德在达拉斯的暗杀事件 （李·哈维·奥斯沃德 于1963年在达拉斯暗杀肯尼迪）
What does that have to do with it?.
这跟暗杀事件有什么关系？
I think he should have looked into it.
我觉得他应调查清楚
There's a lot of serious questions that haven't been answered.
还有很多问题没能得到回答
In the Saturday Evening Post there was a statement...
《周六晚邮报》刊登过
that the CIA knew about Lee Harvey Oswald's trip to Mexico...
说中情局知道李·哈维·奥斯沃德去过墨西哥
only two months before John Kennedy--
就在肯尼迪遇刺之前两个月...
May I help you?
需要帮忙吗？
Damn it. It looks like I'm a prime target.
该死 好像有人盯上我了
First the hubcaps, now my radio antenna.
先是轮毂盖出问题 现在收音机又坏了
Rotten kids.
一群坏孩子
What's the difference?. Channel Eight's got more where these came from.
很要紧吗？八频道有很多这种车吧
That's not the point.
这不是重点
What?.
什么？
- Where do you want to go?. - How about a movie?.
- 你想去哪？- 去看电影吧？
Come on. Go after her!
快 追上她！
Attagirl!
这就对了！
In the crotch! Atta baby! In the crotch!
攻击裆部！对！攻击！
Kill her!
干掉她！
- Kill her! - Pull her hair!
- 干掉她！ - 抓她的头发！
- Tie her up! - Kick her in the back!
- 把她绑起来！ - 踢她后背！
Kick her in the back!
踢后背！
Yea!
好！
Let's see some action!
让我们看点刺激的！
You're just a chicken!
你真是待宰的羔羊！
Go to work. Go to work.
快回场上去
Go! Go! Go!
加油 加油！
- No cheating. - Goes foryou too.
- 不准作弊 - 你也一样
That's right.
没错
All right. Deuces are wild, Robert.
好 我们现在玩“二最大” 罗伯特
All right. Show him what to do.
好 你教他怎么玩
Now, deuces are wild, Robert.
记住 二最大 罗伯特
They count as anything you want 'em to.
你可以随便叫点数
Hold 'em. Hold 'em.
拿好了
Take this one. Throw the rest away.
这张留着 其余牌不要了
- This?. - How many you want?.
- 这张？ - 你要几点？
- I want four. - Four?.
- 四点 - 四点？
- How many you want?. - Five.
- 你要多少？ - 5点
You mean four.
不是说4吗
No cheating, now.
不准作弊啊
- Two aces. What do you got?. - I got two treys.
- 两张A 你是什么牌？ - 两张三
Two treys.
两张三
- What'd you do?. You throw-- - I got two aces.
- 你怎么打的？你把... - 我有两张A
You throwed down my three nines down, didn't you?.
你把我的三张9给扔了吗？
No, he got 'em.
是他拿到的
I didn't get 'em. They're in the deck.
我没拿到 在这堆里吧
He threw 'em down.
他扔掉的
Boy, it's hot. You got anything to drink?.
热死了 有没有喝的？
Miss Horton, you have anything to drink?.
霍顿小姐 你有什么饮料吗？
- There's plenty ofwater in the sink. - I don't want any water.
- 水槽里有的是水 - 我不想喝水
I want a Coke or something. Let's go get a Coke, Robert.
我想喝可乐之类的 我们买可乐去 罗伯特
We'll see you there.
一会儿见
- Where'd your friends go?. - To get a Coke.
- 你的朋友去哪了？- 买可乐去了
Get a Coke?.
买可乐？
- What was you playing?. - Deuces wild.
- 你们刚才在玩什么？ - “二最大”
- Who won?. - Nobody.
- 谁赢了？- 没谁
Nobody.
没谁啊
- What's the matter?. - Nothing.
- 你怎么了？ - 没什么
You're pretty dirty. You've been working them birds.
你身上好脏啊 刚才出去放鸟了吧
You'd better go wash up before we eat supper.
最好洗干净再吃晚饭
Well, go on.
快去
Go on, now. Get.
现在去洗
We thank Thee, Lord, for this food.
主 感谢您赐予食物
Bless it to the nourishment of our bodies. In Thy name we pray.
让我们的身体得到滋养 奉主之名祷告
Amen.
阿门
"The racing pigeon, or homing pigeon...
“赛鸽或者信鸽...”
remains faithful to its mate throughout its life...
“一辈子忠于自己的伴侣”
provided that the mate is present at all times...
“尤其在长途飞行...”
especially when the male bird returns...
“雄鸟归巢后”
after a long flight.
“伴侣会一直护其左右”
In addition, when the pair has young...
“此外 在双方都很年轻时”
this bond is even stronger.
“这种情谊更加牢固”
If, however, the family is separated...
“但是 如果在相当长的时间内”
for an extended period...
“家庭被迫分离”
the male pigeon, not unlike his human counterpart...
“雄鸽和人类一样”
can be relied upon...
“也会在其他地方”
to seek female companionship elsewhere. "
“寻找雌性伴侣”
Roll it up.
关窗
This may be the last time
#也许是最后一次#
May be the last time but I don 't know
#也许是最后一次 但我不知道#
Well, it may be the last time you march on the capitol
#也许是最后一次 在首都游行#
you march on Congress
#也许是最后一次 在国会游行#
Well, it may be the last time you march foryour freedom
#也许是最后一次 为了自由游行#
Thinking, this may be the last time
#也许是最后一次#
Appalachia. You see the si gn?.
是阿巴拉契亚地区的队伍 看到标志了吗？
- Could we get a drink of water first?. - T o hell with the water.
- 我们能先喝点水吗？ - 喝什么水
Let's find this guy.
先把人找到
They're behind the Mexicans, ain't they?.
他们在墨西哥队伍后面？
I heard they were behind the San Francisco contingent.
我听说他们在旧金山队伍后
- This is in this direction here. - I thought it was a blue tent.
- 就是这个方向 - 是吗 我记得是个蓝色帐篷
I don't know how these people listen to this crap.
不知道这些人怎么能住在这泥潭里
I don't know how long this is gonna keep going.
也不知道这样还会持续多久
- Well, where is it?. - Let's go this way.
- 那到底在哪？- 我们走这边
I would hope, now that the California primary is finished...
现在加州初选已经结束
now that these primaries are over...
加州初选已经结束 我希望...
that we could now concentrate on having a dialogue...
我们可以专心致志地
or a debate, I hope, between the vice president and myself...
由我和副总统展开辩论
of what direction we want to go in.
讨论各自的政策方向
Mayor Yorty hasjust sent me a message...
约蒂市长刚刚给我发来消息
that we've been here too long already.
说我们应该散会了
- We love you, Bob. - My thanks to all ofyou...
- 我们爱你 鲍勃 - 感谢所有人...
and now it's on to Chicago, and let's win there.
现在我们要去芝加哥争取胜利
We want Bobby!
支持鲍勃！支持鲍勃！
Oh, no I don 't believe it
#不 我不相信#
You say that you think you know the meaning oflove
#你说你懂爱的意义#
You say love is all we need
#你说我们只需要爱情#
You say with your love
#你说只要有了爱#
You could change all ofthe fools all ofthe hate
#就能消除愚昧和仇恨#
I thinkyou're probably out to lunch
#我觉得你这是说胡话#
You guys here to cover the funeral?.
你们是来报道葬礼的？
Yeah, that's what we're here for.
是的 我们是来报道葬礼的
I didn't hear you come in last night.
昨晚没听到你进来
You score?.
拍到什么了吗？
You left the TV set on.
你昨晚没关电视
You know, you can meet a lot of interesting people in a cocktail lounge.
在鸡尾酒会总能碰到有趣的人
You know that for every man in D.C., there are four and a halfwomen?.
你知道吗 在华盛顿首府 平均每个男人拥有四个半女人
It's a beautiful city, huh?. Wow. Beautiful.
多美丽的城市啊 对吧
Boy, this air-conditioning really gets you.
天哪 这空调真够冷的
Look at these guys.
你看那些人
Couple of hours, they're all set up.
两小时就全准备好了
Twenty, twenty-five camera positions-- like nothing.
轻松搞定二十几台摄影机
They've had experience since we did J.F.K. in '63.
他们从1963年约翰·F·肯尼迪的葬礼报道中得到了经验
Hello, ladies.
女士们好
What are your plans for the summer--
这个夏天有何打算？
this, which will be a very political summer...
这将是个有很浓的政治色彩的夏天
and possibly a very hot one.
并很有可能非常热
Oh, well, now, let's not get into politics.
我们还是不要谈政治了
Well, we always go up to our place...
我们每年都去加拿大安大略
up in Ontario, up in Canada.
自家的度假屋
It's a place called Desbras.
那个地方叫德巴拉
That's D-E-S. It's French.
拼写是D-E-S 是法语
It's not like a girl's name.
不是常见的那个女孩的名字
And, well, about this time ofyear, we always start looking forward...
每年到了这个时候 我们就盼着
to getting away from the city and the crowds and the heat.
远离城市 人群和热浪
It's very primitive up there.
那边的条件很原始
And I think sometimes it's good for the soul...
有时候 离开纷繁的文明社会
to get away from civilization, don't you think so?.
可以净化人的心灵 你觉得呢？
- Hello.
- 你好 - 你好
- Is your mother home?. - Yes. No.
- 你妈妈在家吗？ - 在... 不在
- No?. Is she working?. - Yes.
- 不在？她上班去了？ - 是
What time will she be home?.
她什么时候回家？
- At 1 2:00. - I see.
- 12点 - 这样
- Now, how long have you lived here?. - I don't know.
- 你们在这里住了多久了？ - 我不知道
- You don't know?. - No.
- 你不知道？ - 嗯
Could you tell me where you lived before you moved here?.
能不能告诉我 在搬来这里之前 你们住在哪里？
- Yes. - Where?.
- 嗯 - 那住哪里？
- West Virginia. - I see.
- 西弗吉尼亚州 - 这样
Now, how many rooms do you have?.
你们家有几个房间？
- No-- yeah. Four. - Four rooms.
- 嗯 四个 - 四个房间
- Do you have a TV set?. - Yes.
- 家里有电视吗？ - 有
- Do you have a stereo?.
- 有立体声音响吗？ - 有
And how many brothers and sisters do you have?.
你有几个兄弟姐妹？
- None. - You're the only child?.
- 我没有 - 你是独生子？
- Yes. - And how old are you?.
- 是 - 你今年多大了？
- Thirteen. - Thirteen. Really?.
- 13岁 - 13岁了 真的吗？
- And do you go to church?. - Yes.
- 你平时会去教堂吗？ - 会
That's a good boy.
乖孩子
- Now, what is your father's name?. - Buddy.
- 你父亲叫什么名字？ - 巴迪
- What?.
- 什么？ - 巴迪
- Does he live here at home with you?. - No.
- 他和你们住在一起吗？ - 没有
Could you tell me where I could find him?.
能告诉我他现在在哪里吗？
At Vietnam.
在越南
Let's go see what damage we done up here.
看看我们这一枪的威力
- Look at the holes there. - Golly!
- 看看这些洞 - 天哪
Look around and see ifyou can find another.
四处找找 还有一个
Hell, I got something here. Come here.
过来看看这边
I ain't gonna waste this, though.
这可不能浪费了
Drink this.
喝了它
Come on.
走了
- You want to shoot it?. - Uh-uh.
- 你想射那个瓶子吗？ - 不要
It ain't gonna hurt you. Just put a shell in like that.
不会伤到你的 像这样 放个弹壳进去
- It's safe. It won't hurt you at all. - I don't want to shoot it.
- 很安全的 绝不会受伤 - 我不想打
Draw it back.
拉回来
Knock it off of there. That's all you got to do.
然后开枪 就这么简单
Come on. Let's go.
好了 走吧
Come on. Let's go look at pigeons.
我们看看鸽子去
Nothing's missing. I looked.
我看过了 什么都没丢
You out of shape, pal?. What's in the basket?.
你有不舒服吗？那篮子里是什么？
Dinner.
晚饭
Why don'tyou admit it? Go on.Just say it.
你干嘛不承认？说啊
You're a bastard.
你就是个混蛋
Admit it to me.
承认吧
Admit it to yourself.
不要自欺欺人了
You're a rotten, egotistical, selfish...
你是个腐败的 自负又自私的
punchy cameraman.
糊里糊涂的摄影记者
Well?.
对吧？
Well?. Well?.
对吧？对吧？
Look at this here. Look.
看这里
How do you like it?. Gus wired it up for me.
喜欢吗？盖斯帮我安装的
Look back there. Fiber optics. Great, huh?.
看看 是光纤 很不错吧？
See the TV?. Lights.
还有电视 台灯
- Look at that. - John.
- 看看呐 - 约翰
Do you remember when we saw Mondo Cane?
还记得我们看《世界残酷奇谭》吗？
- We didn't see Mondo Cane. - Well, I saw it.
- 我们没看过吧 - 好吧 我看过
I saw it, too, but I don't remember seeing it with you.
我也看过 但我不记得是跟你一起看的
Well, anyway, that's not the point.
反正 这不是重点
What's the point?.
那是什么？
Well, you remember that scene...
你记不记得那个场景
on an island, where they tested an atom bomb?.
在一个岛上 他们测试了原子弹？
Yeah.
嗯
Well, there were these big turtles...
那里有巨大的海龟
you know, tortoises, who, at a certain time in their lives...
你知道的 那种乌龟嘛 在特定的年龄阶段
would walk to the sea to lay their eggs.
会走到海里产蛋
And they found that the radiation thing...
然后他们发现 原子弹的辐射
threw the turtles' sense of direction...
影响了海龟的方向感
so instead of heading to the sea, they went inland and died.
它们没有走到海里 而是走向内陆 死在了那里
Oh, I'm crying.
噢 我哭了
Damn it!
该死的
Look, somebody took those movies, right?.
有人去岛上拍了这电影 对吧？
I mean, do you think did they or didn't they...
那你觉得他们有没有...
after they took those movies--
在拍完电影之后...
Do you think-- Did they reach down and turn those turtles around...
会不会把那些海龟领到正确的方向？
or did they put them in a jeep and drive them back?.
或者开车带它们回到海里？
How the hell do I know what they did?. Those were Italian cameramen.
我怎么会知道？那些摄影师是意大利人
I give up. I surrender.
我放弃 我投降
No calories.
嘿 零热量哦
I'd rather keep my kidneys for a while.
我还是善待我的肾吧
"Research physicians at the Istituto del Salvador Muni in Rome...
“罗马救世主医院的研究医师...”
reveal today the results of tests...
“在今天公布了一项测试结果”
involving a new device to be worn by expectant mothers...
“这是一种新型设备”
during the entire course of their pregnancy.
“准妈妈在怀孕期间全程携带”
This device consists of a steel and plastic cylinder...
“设备由钢和塑料圆筒组成”
which can be controlled to create a partial vacuum...
“可以在母亲腹部制造局部真空”
around the mother's abdomen, reducing atmospheric pressure on the fetus.
“减少胎儿所受的压力”
This pressure--
“这种压力”
which is at sea level 1 4.7 pounds per square inch--
“在海平面上相当于14.7磅每平方寸”
can be reduced by as much as 50%.
“可以减少多达50%”
It was Dr. Giacobo Marciani...
“贾科博·玛西亚尼医生”
director of the hospital's research institute...
“医院研究所的所长”
who first made public the results of the test involving the new device.
“首先公布了这种新设备的测试结果”
Although it is anticipated that the price...
“虽然根据预计”
in the early stages of development, at least...
“面世初期的价格”
will be prohibited-- prohibiti-- prohibitive--
“可能会过高 令人望而却步”
official comment on the new device...
“梵蒂冈官方”
has not yet been forthcoming from the Vatican."
“尚未对新设备发表评论”
Don't!
不要！
You're crazy!
你这个疯子！
No! Give me my sheet back! John!
把床单还给我！约翰！
Give me that!
还给我！
I got you! You bastard! Son of a bitch!
抓到你了！混蛋！
Let go of me, you fuck!
放开我 混蛋！
Help! No, not on the floor!
救命！不要把我放地上！
Jesus, you!
天哪 你！
Help! Put me down! Help!
救命！放我下来！
You bastard! Let go of me, you prick!
混蛋！放开我！
Naughty, naughty. I got neighbors.
真淘气 小心邻居听到
- Son of a bitch! - I got neighbors. Be quiet.
- 你这个混蛋！ - 隔壁有邻居的 小声点
Catch you in the act. They'll bust your arms. I like you.
被抓个现行 他们会折断你的胳膊的 我喜欢你
Me too.
我也喜欢你
I'm gonna knock the shit out ofyou.
我要把你揍扁
Ouch!
嗷！
There he goes.
又来了
One good deed a year.
每年做一次好人
I heard that.
这话我听过了
- You dropped your newspaper. - Who are you?.
- 你的报纸掉了 - 你是谁？
"Horton. 4444 North Clifton."
“北克里夫顿路4444号 霍顿家”
I think this belongs to your little brother.
这应该是你弟弟的
I don't have a brother. It belongs to my son.
我没有弟弟 这是我儿子的
Mr. Horton go for green beans?.
霍顿先生喜欢吃绿豆？
- Man. - Not on the car.
天哪 不要上车顶
Not on the car. Come on. Get off the car.
不要爬上去 快下来
Come on. Off the car. Come on.
快下车
Get out of there.
你出来
Come on. Out of the car.
都出来
This is an official car. Come on.
这是单位的车 别胡闹
- All those kids out there yours?. - No. They belong to my neighbors.
- 外面那些小孩子都是你的？ - 不 他们是邻居家的
- Are you from the mountains?. - West Virginia.
- 你是从山区搬来的？ - 西弗吉尼亚州
- Just spent three weeks there. - You did?.
- 我刚去那边呆了三个礼拜 - 是吗？
We sure starve a lot when the stamps run out.
“粮票用完 我们一定会挨饿”
Trouble is, you can't get no "tobaccy" on stamps.
“问题是 粮票不能买烟”
So you know about the stamps.
那你也知道粮票的事啊
No, not really. I did this documentary. Those words are on a tape.
其实也不是 我拍了一部纪录片 里面出现了这些词
Hello, Marian, this is Gus.
喂 玛丽安 我是盖斯
Page Katselas on number 51 2.
请呼叫卡塞拉斯 号码是512
Have him report to the wagon immediately.
让他立即汇报情况
Ten-four. Ten-four.
收到
I could've let the bird go. He would've flown back...
我本可以直接放飞 它可能可以自己飞回来
but I don't know how he would've carried the basket.
但我不知道该怎样一起把篮子送来
It might've flown back to West Virginia.
它可能直接飞回西弗吉尼亚了
Harold spends all his time trying to retrain him.
哈洛花了很多时间重新训练它
- How long you been up here?. - Not too long.
- 你们在这住了多久了？ - 没多久
- John, call the office. - You got a telephone around here?.
- 约翰 给办公室回电话 - 你家有电话吗？
In the hall.
在走道
Katselas here.
我是卡塞拉斯
Yeah, but he's right outsi--
是啊 但他就在外面...
He did, huh?. Yeah, all right.
是吗？好吧
Anything else?.
还有别的事吗？
All right. Thankyou.
好的 谢谢
You tell Harold the bad guy from the parking lot brought his bird back.
告诉哈洛 停车场那个坏人把鸽子送回来了
- You tell him. Hear?. - I will.
- 一定记得告诉他 - 会的
You mind turning this off?.
麻烦可以关掉吗？
We're gonna make sound. Would you shut this off?.
我们要录音 这个可以关掉吗？
- Shut it off! - All right.
- 关掉！ - 好吧
Where was the money really located?.
之前那钱到底在哪？
Was it stuffed in the seat?.
藏在座椅下面？
It was in an envelope on the floor.
在地上一个信封里
What kind of envelope?.
怎样的信封？
What kind of an envelope was it?.
是怎样的信封？
Ask him. He's counting the money there.
问他啊 他正数钱呢
He's counting the money. How much money is it?.
他在数钱 一共有多少钱？
- How much money is it?. - Don't ask him.
- 一共多少钱？ - 不要问他
I want to know from you. How much money did you have?.
我问的是你 你数了有多少钱？
How much did you count?. Did you count the money?.
你数了一共多少？你数了吗？
- $1 0,000. - You sure it was $1 0,000?.
- 一万块 - 你确定吗？
It wasn't 9,000?. Wasn't 1 1,000?.
不是九千？不是一万一？
9,000?. $1 0,000, right?.
九千？刚好一万吗？
It was 9,000. I put 1,000 of mine to make it 1 0,000.
是啊 是九千 我自己放了一千块进去 凑够一万
What you gonna do?. Get funny now?.
你这是干嘛？搞笑吗？
Gonna start putting me on?. Let's not play games with each other.
你想耍我吗？别使花招了
I'm here to find out why you turned in $1 0,000. Where did you get it?.
我是来查清楚 你为什么交还了一万块 你在哪里捡到的？
Aren't you thankful I did turn in $1 0,000?.
我还了一万块 你还不感谢我？
Maybe not. I'm a policeman. I'm just here to find out the facts.
不 我是警察 我是来查明真相的
Just tell her we coverthe news. We do not manufacture violence.
告诉她 我们是报道新闻的 不会制造暴力
Talk to her, okay?.
跟她谈谈 好吗？
Mrs. Harris, I'm re-- Well?.
哈里斯太太 我...
Remember the shot of the cabby who turned the money in?.
还记得上次我们拍了一个出租车司机交还了钱的吗？
- Forget it. - There's a story there, Carlin.
- 算了吧 - 这故事很精彩的 卡林
A lot of people are interested. I think it'll go on the Sunday reports.
很多人感兴趣的 值得跟进 我觉得可以当周日新闻
No. I got a convention coming up, a war...
不行 接下来的新闻是大会的召开 还有战争...
I got baseball, a nervous city...
还有棒球比赛 和这个紧张躁动的城市
plus I got chickenshit cameramen that are afraid...
另外 我的摄影记者胆小如鼠
to go into the ghetto without police protection.
没有警察保护就不敢进贫民区
No. Stay out of those neighborhoods...
不行 你别再去那些街区了
until I send you in there.
除非我派你去
- I want film and lab. - They got film.
- 我需要胶片和暗室 - 他们有胶片了
- Would you please stop bothering me?.
- 我需要胶片和暗室 - 朋友 能不能别再烦我了
Mr. Evans's office on line six.
埃文斯先生的办公室来电话了 在6线
Write up a voucher. Yes, sir. Good morning.
写张收据 喂您好 早上好
Hey, TV man. Are we gonna be on TV?.
嘿 电视台的 我们会上电视吗？
We wanna be on TV.
我们想上电视
- TV, that's for us. - Hey, TV man! What's happening?.
- 快拍我们 - 嘿 电视台的！发生什么事了？
...slaughtered Philadelphia 9-0.
...9比0横扫费城队
And finally, it was the Mets walloping the Pirates.
最后 大都会队击败了海盗队
- Locked?. - Yeah.
- 锁好了？ - 是
-You know you're two blocks away?. -I had some trouble in there last ni ght.
- 你知道我们还有两个街区才到吧？ - 昨晚碰到了点麻烦
Thought we'd keep the equipment safe.
觉得停这里设备更安全
White bread on sandwiches is not too cool.
白面包做三明治可不好吃
- Come on, now. - No. That's out of it. O-U-T. Out.
- 别这样嘛 - 不行 绝对不行
I don't think we have any other kind, but I'll take a look-see.
我们应该没有其他的面包了 不过我找找
Frank, I dug your name in the paper.
弗兰克 我在报纸上看到了你的名字 发生什么事了？
You're somewhat of a celebrity now. Want to fill me in?.
你现在也算是名人了啊 跟我说说怎么回事吧？
Well, I'm not really a celebrity...
我也算不得是名人
but, yeah, I found the bread, and I turned it in.
我拣到了一笔钱 然后交给了警察
- You turned it in. - Uh-huh.
- 你交给警察了 - 嗯
Were you acting as a Negro or a black man?.
你这种行为是更像是黑鬼还是黑人？
I'm concerned about this.
你怎么想？我挺担心这个
What do you mean, was I acting as a Negro or black man?.
什么意思？什么黑鬼还是黑人？
Ifyou were acting as a black man, you would've kept the money.
因为如果是黑人的话 你会把钱留下
Ifyou were acting as a Negro, you turned it in.
如果是黑鬼 那你就会交给警察
You're my man. You're my man and everything.
你是我最喜欢的一个 我没有恶意
- How much money was that?. - $1 0,000.
- 你拣到了多少钱 弗兰克？- 一万块
$1 0,000?. You kidding?.
一万块？你是开玩笑吗？
Dig, now, look. You know--
听着 你瞧...
Do you realize how much ammunition and guns...
你知道一万块能买多少
$1 0,000 would've bought?.
枪支弹药吗？
Well, I'm not quite there yet.
我没想那么多
But I'm talking about, you got to be alive to be honest.
但我的意思是 想诚实 首先得活着啊
- Whatyou doing around here, man? - Just buying some cigarettes.
- 你来这里干嘛？ - 买烟
You ain't got no right coming here to buy no cigarettes.
你无权来这里买烟
Guys like you get shot all up, you know?.
像你这种人会挨枪子的 知道么？
-Yeah. -Don't come here for cigarettes.
- 嗯 - 不要来这里买烟了
You know what I mean?.
明白我的意思吗？
We have a visitor.
有客人来了
- Frank Baker live here?.
- 弗兰克·贝克住这里吗？- 弗兰克·贝克住这里吗？
- Frank Baker, cabdriver?.
- 弗兰克·贝克 那个出租车司机？- 弗兰克·贝克 那个出租车司机？
- Does he live here?.
- 他住这里吗？- 他住这里吗？
- Yeah. Does he live here?.
- 嗯 他住这里吗？- 他住这里吗？
There's no Frank cabdriver here.
这里没有叫弗兰克·贝克的出租车司机
You don't know him?. He's a cabdriver. I did a story on him. I'm a reporter.
你不认识他？他开出租车的 我报道了他的新闻 我是记者
- What's his name again?. - Frank Baker.
- 他叫什么名字来着？- 弗兰克·贝克
- Come on. You're putting the guy on.
- 弗兰克·贝克 - 行了 杰夫 你别耍他了
This is the guy who put me on television.
是他让我上的电视 还是彩色的呢
- How you doing?. - Very well. I don't want to bust in.
- 你好吗？ - 挺好 我不想就这样进来打扰
I just wondered ifyou got five minutes to talk.
想问问你有没有五分钟的时间聊聊
- Let's do it over a drink. - Good.
- 我们边喝边聊吧 - 好
You know, Chicago cops...
你看 芝加哥的警察们
are getting funnier-looking every day.
穿着打扮越来越搞笑
- I'm not a cop. I'm a soundman. - Bet you got credentials too.
- 我不是警察 我是录音的 - 你肯定也有证件吧
The FBI supplies the best credentials.
联邦调查局的证件做得最好
We know that one of the best ways...
我们知道 你们这些人很清楚
for spying on black people is to impersonate TV men.
监视黑人最好的办法就是伪装成电视台的
We're talking to Frank about doing a story.
我和约翰一起来的 想问弗兰克要不要拍段新闻
- Yeah?. What's that?. - That's my Pageboy.
- 是吗？那这是什么？ - 我的传呼机
- Your Pageboy?. - Yeah.
- 传呼机？ - 是啊
Hey, Richard, come and dig this cat's Pageboy.
嘿 理查德 过来看看这小子的传呼机
Now, what do you do with "my Pageboy"?.
那这个“传呼机” 你用来做什么？
Well, I don't do anything. It just hangs there.
什么也不用做 只是挂在这里
If they want me to go someplace or do something, they call me on it.
如果电视台想让我去哪里或者做什么 他们会呼我
You mean, they give you orders on this.
你是说 他们用这个来传达命令
Yeah.
是啊
Man, you mean to tell me they talk to you, and you can't talk back?.
那是不是说 他们可以跟你讲话 但你不能回复？
He means he's a receiver and not a sender.
他的意思是 他接收命令 而不是发号施令的
Looks like they're calling you now.
看样子他们正在呼你
What, you a white flunky or something?.
你是白人马屁精什么的吗？
Wrong. You got a bad idea about--
你搞错了
I forgot something downstairs. I'll meet you in the car.
我把东西忘在楼下了 一会儿车子那边见吧
All right.
好吧
Coming back. He's coming back.
回来了 他回来了
There he goes.
然后他又走了
A honky flunky.
势利的白鬼子
Look, man, I've been on television...
听着 我也上过电视了
I've been in the newspapers, and it's made my life total confusion.
也上过报纸 这件事扰乱了我的生活
I find $1 0,000 in a cab. I'm boob enough to turn it in...
我都干什么了？我在出租车里拣到一万块 还够傻地上交了
and I get my butt kicked by everybody in the world.
全世界的人都在嘲笑我
- No, man. - That's just it, Frank.
- 这样可不行 - 这只是一部分 弗兰克
It's a human interest story. People identify.
这会是有人情味的故事 人们会认同的
- It'll be constructive. - Are you coming, Frank?.
- 那可会很有用 - 你去不去 弗兰克？
I'll give you a call, and we'll have another talk about it.
我再给你电话吧 可以再详谈
Thankyou.
十分感谢
Excuse me, TV man, you wanted someone for an interview, right?.
不好意思 电视台大哥 你想找人做采访 对吗？
I haven't got time right now, dear. I gotta run.
是的 但我现在没时间了 得赶紧走了
But I wanted to talk to you. See, I'm a black actress.
但我想跟你谈谈 我是个黑人演员
- Listen, honey-- I haven't got time-- - Don't "honey" me.
- 你听我说 亲爱的 我没时间... - 别叫我“亲爱的”
I'm a black actress. I demand respect. I'm not looking for--
我是个黑人演员 我需要被尊重 我只是想找...
- You call the station. - No. You said you wanted somebody.
- 你可以打电话去电视台 - 不 你刚才才说你需要找人采访
You want to hear-- know what's going on, what black people are doing?.
你想不想知道 这里都发生了什么 黑人过着怎样的生活？
- I'm not interested. - Wait, wait.
- 我没兴趣 - 等等 等等
- Don't "honey" me. - You got to start respecting our women.
- 别叫我“亲爱的” - 你得学会尊重女性
I have no disrespect in mind. I gotta leave. I don't have time.
我无意冒犯 但我真的要走了 没时间了
I want to talk to you about what I'd like to do.
我想跟你谈谈我想怎么做
You people are always busy putting your kind of people on.
你们总是顾着为你们这种人忙活
I want to talk to you about what I want.
我想谈的是我想要的
- Listen, dear. - I told you about that "dear."
- 听我说 亲爱的 - 我说了 不要叫“亲爱的”
- I'm trying to be very respectful. - We demand--
- 我这是尊重你 - 我们要求...
- You demand what?. - Demand respect.
- 要求什么？ - 要求尊重
- Handle it. - I'll try.
- 去劝一下 - 我尽量吧
- Don't call me "honey." - Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
- 别叫我“亲爱的” - 等一下 等一下
-This is the guy that came by the house. -I know the guy.
- 这个人是主动来我们家的 - 我知道他是谁
So don't give him a bad time.
那就别为难他了
Leave him alone. He's all right.
别跟他吵了 他没有恶意
- Come on, baby. - He's a jive--
- 别这样 - 他是个混蛋
Wait a minute. I want to talk to you. Come in.
- 等一下 我想跟你谈谈 - 进来
Let me askyou something. Are you being friendly?.
我先问一下 你会平心静气地谈吗？
Am I being friendly?. I just saved your life.
平心静气？我刚刚才救了你一命
- If I got to be afraid-- - You understand I just saved your life?.
- 如果我变得害怕... - 你知道我刚才救了你一命吗？
If I got to be afraid foryour argument to work, you got no argument.
如果我要很害怕 你们才能吵起来 那就没得吵了
I want you to understand I saved your life.
我只要你明白 刚才我救了你一命
You came down here to do some sort of jive interview.
你来这边做什么没用的访谈
You did that. Came down here with 1 5 minutes of a black sensibility...
只是拍了15分钟黑人的片段
and so you don't understand that.
你根本不明白
You came down here to shoot 1 5 minutes...
你只拍了15分钟
ofwhat has taken 300 years to develop.
这里的一切却沉淀了300年的历史
- Grief, you know?. - I'm not interested in grief--
- 这是悲痛 你明白吗？ - 我对悲痛没兴趣...
All we're trying to explain to you is that you don't understand.
你不明白的事 我们在尽力向你解释
I do something. I do it well. That's my job.
我做了事 且做得很好 这是我的工作
You don't do it black enough. You can't, because you're not black. We are.
但你拍黑人拍得不够 你做不到 因为你不是黑人 我们才是
When you come and say you've come to do something of human interest...
当你来这里说自己要拍点人情味的东西
it makes a person wonder whether you're going to do something...
这让人很疑惑 你是要拍
of interest to other humans, or whether you consider the person human...
其他人感兴趣的东西 还是说你真正把
in whom you're interested.
自己有兴趣拍摄的人 当成人来看待
You have to understand that too.
你也得明白这一点
You can't just walk in out ofyour arrogance...
你不能如此傲慢地走进来
and expect things to be like they are...
然后期望一切都像原来那样
because when you walked in, you brought La Salle Street with you...
因为你走进来时 带着拉塞尔街（芝加哥的金融街）的气息
City Hall and all the mass communications media.
以及市政厅 和所有大众传播媒介 都一起来了
And you are the exploiters. You're the ones who distort...
你们是开拓者 但正是你们曲解了我们
and ridicule and emasculate us, and that ain't cool.
嘲弄和削弱我们 这是不对的
You don't want to know, man. You don't know the people.
你根本不想去了解 也根本不了解这些人
You don't show the people.
你没有展现出这些人真正的样子
Here's some cat who's down and out, you dig?.
有个一无是处的小子
He's nobody, so he says to his old man...
他无足轻重 他问自己的父亲
"I'm nobody. I'm gonna die,
“我无足轻重 我要死了”
and ain't nobody gonna know I lived," dig?.
“没有人知道我曾活过” 你懂吗？
So the cat finds a brick and throws it through Charlie's window...
于是这小子决定找一块砖头 砸碎别人家的玻璃
or he takes a gun and he shoots.
或者他会弄一把枪去杀人
Then the cat lives, man. He really lives, dig?.
然后他才算活过了 真正地活过了
A hundred million people see the cat on the tube.
上百万的人通过电视知道了这小子的事
They say, "The former invisible man lives."
他们说 “曾经的隐形人活过来了”
Everybody knows about his wife and kids-- everything, you dig?.
大家都知道了他的老婆孩子 和其他一切
'Cause the tube is life, man. Life.
因为电视就是人生 就是人生啊
You make him an Emmy, man. You make him the TV star of the hour...
你让他出名了 成为了电视明星
on the 6:00, the 1 0:00 and the 1 2:00 news.
连续出现在6点 10点 和12点的新闻里
'Cause what the cat is saying is truth, man.
因为他说的是事实
Why don't you find out what really is?.
你为什么不去找出真相？
Why you always got to wait till somebody gets killed?.
为什么总是等到有人被杀才行动？
'Cause somebody is gonna get killed.
因为总有人会被杀死
Is that thing loaded?.
这玩意上膛了吗？
As a matter of fact, they call it a shotgun.
事实上 这个叫“散弹枪”
It looks about 1 2-gauge.
看上去好像是12口径的
- Let's go over here. - Okay.
- 我们过去吧 - 好
There's a good background. Very good.
这背景不错 很好
- We can't shoot here. - What do you mean?.
- 不能在这里拍 - 为什么？
Too noisy. Those gunshots will wipe us out.
太吵了 枪声会掩盖我们的声音
It's always too noisy, isn't it?. Let's go back over here.
一向都这么吵的 不是吗？好吧 我们回去那边
- Good for you?. - Yeah, fine.
- 这里可以吗？ - 好
- Pepsi machine. Good enough?. - Fine.
- 百事贩卖机 可以吗？ - 好
Excuse me.
不好意思
- What do I do now?. - Just speak in a normal tone ofvoice.
- 我该怎么做？ - 用平常的语调说话就行
Rolling here. Rolling.
开始录了
Well, there's been about a 46% increase...
自从去年发生暴动后
in pistol registration since last year's riot.
枪支登记数量上涨了46%
We're getting our business from people...
我们这里的顾客是...
who want to protect their families and homes.
那些想保护家人的人
- Can you hold on a minute?. - Excuse me.
- 可以等一下吗？ - 不好意思
- The damn thing's stuck. - Point that down.
- 这该死的东西卡住了 - 枪口朝下
I've only got one head. There we go. See?. This release.
我只有一颗脑袋 这样 看到没？这样打开
There. Okay?.
这样 懂了吗？
- Thankyou. - There you go.
- 谢谢 - 好了
- Not bad. - You ready again?.
- 不错嘛 - 可以继续了？
You want to start again?.
你想重新说吗？
Well, I don't know what you're looking for.
我不知道你们想问什么
If a person has a driver's license...
如果一个人有驾照
he has to know how to drive.
他就得知道怎样开车
If a person gets a gun, he has to know how to use it.
如果一个人有枪 他就得知道怎么使用
How he uses it or what he uses it for is a personal right.
他怎样使用或者用来做什么 是他的个人权利
Sorry.
不好意思
- Dick, let me have a dime. - Sure, John.
- 迪克 借我一毛钱硬币 - 好
There you go.
给
I asked him where he was. He said, "I was on vacation."
我问他在哪 他说 “我在度假”
Hey, loverboy.
嘿 大众情人
Dede's looking foryou.
迪迪在找你
- Looking for me?. - Johnny.
- 你找我吗？- 约翰尼
- There might be a little problem. - What is it?.
- 可能出了点小问题 - 什么问题？
Carlin came around yesterday kind of mad.
卡林昨天来过 有点生气
Tell me something new.
别说这些老新闻了
Johnny, you know the outtakes for that footage?.
约翰 你知道那段影片的未采用片段吗？
- You know, the draft-card burners?. - Yeah.
- 那些烧征兵证的人？ - 我知道
Did you give that to the light show kids?.
是你把它们交给了负责打光的人吗？
For Christ's sakes, don't be cute. What the hell did he say?.
老天爷 迪迪 别绕弯子了 他到底说了什么？
He didn't say anything definite really.
他没有明确地说什么
He just complained about you being out when he needed you...
他只是抱怨说 需要你的时候你不在
and screwing around, shooting stupid interviews.
到处乱晃 拍些无聊的访问 这种的
What the hell is up?. Don't tell me what you think.
到底怎么回事？别告诉我你是怎么想的
Just tell me what kind of shit's flying around.
告诉我到底发生了什么事
Jesus, let go.
天哪 放手
I'll tell you.
好吧 我告诉你
Well, for about a year now...
大约一年前开始
the station's been letting the cops and the FBI...
电视台允许警方和联邦调查局
study our footage.
看我们拍的素材
You're putting me on. You're kidding me. What am I, a fink?.
你这是耍我吧 开玩笑吗？我这算什么 线人吗？
How can I go out and cover a story?.
我这样还怎样去做报道？
It's a wonder more cameras haven't been smashed.
其他摄像机没被砸坏真是个奇迹
I want to know why nobody told me what the hell's been going on...
我想知道 为什么没人告诉过我这回事
because you can bet in the streets, they know.
因为他们知道 我们在外有多拼命
You should've told me, Dede.
你早该告诉我的 迪迪
- Just a sec, will you?. - Is he here?. Where is he?.
- 你等一等 - 他在吗？他在哪？
I want to see him.
我要见他
He won't be in this morning. This is foryou.
他今早不会来了 这是给你的
Where the hell is he?. Why won't he be in?.
他到底在哪？为什么不来？
What the hell is this crap?.
这是什么玩意？
I don't know what day it plays. Wha--
我不知道它哪天会播出
That was a business call.
这是公事电话
Accounting.
财务部
Did you get a severance notice for John Katselas?.
你们收到约翰·卡塞拉斯的遣散通知了吗？
Just a minute.
稍等
Yes, I have it here. Who's calling?
是 我收到了 你是哪位？
I'd tell them to stuff their lousy job in a minute.
我会叫他们马上搞好自己的破事
Well, you know that. I would.
你知道的 我会这样
I would.
我会的
As far as I'm concerned, I'm with you, John.
就我来说 我是支持你的 约翰
I'll tell the bastards, "IfJohn goes, then I walkwith him."
我会告诉那些混蛋 “如果约翰要走 我也跟着走”
Well, I gotta get moving.
我得走了
Take it easy, Gus.
悠着点 盖斯
Remember me?.
还记得我吗？
Yeah.
嗯
Yeah, I almost didn't recognize you in that outfit.
你换了身衣服 差点没认出来
I work over there at Motorola.
我在那边的摩托罗拉公司上班
Well...
那...
it's been good seeing you.
很高兴见到你
How's the pigeon boy doing?.
养鸽子的小男孩怎样了？
Real good.Just fine.
不错 挺好的
- You always eat here?. - It's pretty bad, isn't it?.
- 你总在这里吃饭吗？ - 很难吃吧？
Most times I bring my own.
通常我会自己带便当
Where you headed?.
你往哪边走？
Did you finish your salad?.
沙拉吃完了吗？
You want some of mine?.
想吃一点我的吗？
Sure?.
真的不要？
What's the matter?.
怎么了？
Maybe it's just that he's not used to company, huh?.
或许他只是不习惯有人一起吃饭 对吧？
What'd you do back home?.
你在老家是做什么的？
I was a schoolteacher.
我以前是老师
You were?. Why aren't you teaching here?.
是吗？那为什么不来这里教书？
Things are very different up here.
这里一切都不同
Down home I taught five grades in one room for one thing.
在老家 我在同一间教室教五个年级同样的东西
Wow.
哇
Like the little red schoolhouse.
就像小红校舍一样（美国第一所进步主义教育学校）
Kind of. But...
有点吧 但...
see, they don't recognize me as a teacher up here.
在这里 他们不认可我的任教资格
The education that I had down home isn't good enough for them...
我在老家受过的教育
for me to teach here, so I can't.
不够在这里教书用 所以不行
But I'll tell you, I don't think I'd want to anyway.
但我跟你说 其实我也不想在这里教
I wouldn't want to teach in the schools in this neighborhood.
我不想在这片社区的学校里教书
- Why not?. - They don't teach you nothing.
- 为什么？ - 这里的学校什么都不教的
It's a Chicago school. They got to teach you something.
这可是在芝加哥 他们总会教点什么的
They don't. They run a television in there.
他们不教的 只是开电视给我们看
Well, they use TV these days.
现在教书都要用到电视
They use educational--
他们有教育性质的...
Yeah, but not that kind ofTV.
我知道 但不是那种电视节目
You watch anything you want. They don't try--
他们随便你看什么 都不会...
When you ask them to--
就算你问他们
that you want to do some work...
说自己想学点什么
they say, "No, you do what I tell you."
他们会说 “不 照我说的做”
- They let you watch TV, is that it?. - Yeah, that's all.
- 他们让你们看电视 就这样？ - 是 就这样
- They don't do nothing else. - Don't you like TV?.
- 什么别的都不做 - 你不是喜欢看电视吗？
Yeah, but--
是啊 但是...
You're probably doing what you like.
你在做你喜欢的事情嘛
- Where you from?. - Right here. Chicago.
- 你是哪里人？ - 芝加哥本地人
C.Y.O. welterweight boxer, 1 958.
1958年CYO锦标赛的次中量级拳击手
You ever boxed?. Or do you just wrestle when you fight?.
你打过拳击吗？还是说你打架时只是乱来？
People down here use sticks, rocks...
这边的人用棍子 石头...
guns, and everything down here in here.
枪 一切能用到的东西
- Nah, you don't use rocks, do you?. - Yeah.
- 你不会用石头的吧？ - 不会
I don't. They do.
我不用 但他们用
- Only dirty fighters use rocks. - And guns and sticks.
- 卑鄙的人才会用石头打架 - 还有枪和棍子
You got a gun?.
你有枪吗？
Play gun?.
玩具枪呢？
That's good.
很好
I shot a gun when I was eight-- I mean, ten years old.
我八岁时就开过枪了 我是说 十岁的时候
- Where?. - West Virginia.
- 在哪里？ - 西弗吉尼亚州
I'll take him with me to C.Y.O. maybe...
或许我可以带他去CYO拳击赛
and let him hit the bag.
让他打沙袋
Can I watch TV?.
我能去看电视吗？
Help me put the plates in the sink, and then you can go watch TV.
帮我把盘子放到水槽里 才能去看电视
I'll give you a hand here.
我来帮你吧
Is your bird okay?.
你的小鸟还好吗？
The other day, I thought you were stealing something off my car.
那天在停车场 我以为你是偷我车里的东西
I don't steal!
我可不偷东西！
Anyway, what's so great about your shitty car?.
而且 你那辆破车有什么了不起的？
I brought your bird back, didn't I?.
我把你的小鸟带回来了 不是吗？
Anyway, it's not my car.
而且那也不是我的车
Beverly Hillbillies, normally scheduled forthis time...
今晚本时段的《比弗利山人》
will not be seen tonight.
将暂停播映
Instead, we bringyou the third part ofa network special...
今晚播出 本台特别节目的第三部分
on John F. Kennedy, Martin L uther King...
关于约翰·肯尼迪 马丁·路德·金
and Robert Kennedy.
以及罗伯特·肯尼迪的特辑
Why'd they fire you?.
他们为什么会解雇你？
Can you get another job?.
你能找到别的工作吗？
Can you get welfare?. I mean, unemployment?.
有补偿金吗？我是指 失业补偿金
Do I look worried?.
我看上去很忧虑吗？
Too many questions. Why they canned me?.
你问太多问题了 他们为什么解雇我？
I'm not sure I know the answer.
我不确定自己知道答案
I started a story about a cabdriver who found all that cash...
我在做一篇报道 一位出租车司机捡到一笔现金
somebody lost and, for unknown reasons, wouldn't claim.
别人落在车上 但不知什么原因 没有来认领
Why?.
为什么？
There's only one kind of money a guy would be afraid to claim.
只有一种钱是没人敢认领的
I had some idea maybe there was a connection...
我有种感觉 觉得这事
between guns, vigilante groups...
跟枪支和民间治安队有关
maybe getting ready for a blowup this summer, you know?.
也许这个夏天来个大爆发 之类的
Then I got sort of sidetracked-- interested, so to speak.
然后新闻没有遭到重视 但我更感兴趣了
But nobody said anything about this.
但也没人说过什么
My director just told my union local...
我的领导只是告诉我的地方工会
I had taken company film without authorization.
说我未经允许擅用公司胶片
You see, it gets pretty complicated.
你看 这事挺复杂的
People rarely say the real reasons for things.
人们很少说出一件事的真实缘由
Big corporations never do.
大公司尤其从来不说
Just politics...
只有政策
plain bureaucratic politics.
纯粹的官僚主义政策
I guess it's the season up here.
我猜 这里的风气就是这样吧
Anyway, we only been in Chicago a little while...
反正我们才来芝加哥不久
not even long enough for me to vote.
还没取得投票资格
Come on. Tell me how you managed to teach five grades in one classroom.
好了 跟我说说你是怎样成功地在一个教室里教五个年级吧
I didn't manage. One thing I did was--
我没有成功 我做了一件事...
Well, I just had three in the third grade...
三年级只有三个学生
so I put one boy up to fourth...
所以我让一个男生升到四年级
and a boy and girl back to second.
另外一个男生和一个女生降到二年级
That way I only had four grades.
这样就只剩四个年级了
Is that the new math?.
这是新型的数学吗？
Gather with the saints at the river
#与众圣徒相聚于河畔#
That flows by the throne ofGod
#河水流经上帝的宝座#
Shall we gather at the river
#我们都到河边去#
Where bright Angel's feet have trod
#天使立于其中#
With these Christians at the river
#河边的基督徒们#
That flows by the throne of God
#河水流经上帝的宝座#
Yes, we shall gather at the river
#我们都到河边去#
The beautiful, beautiful river
#那条河美不胜收#
Gather with the saints at the river
#与众圣徒相聚于河畔#
That flows by the throne of God
#河水流经上帝的宝座#
Yes, we shall gather at the river
#是 我们都到河边去#
The beautiful, beautiful river
#河流美不胜收#
Gather with the saints at the river
#与众圣徒相聚于河畔#
That flows by the throne of God
#河水流经上帝的宝座#
Well, I don 't know what will happen now.
我不知道现在会发生什么
We've got some difficult days ahead...
我们将面临艰难的日子
but it doesn 't really matter with me now...
但我现在真的不在意
because I've been to the mountaintop.
因为我已上过山的顶峰
I don 't mind.
我不在意
Like anybody, I would like to live a long life.
像其他人一样 我也希望活得长久
L ongevity has its place...
追求长寿是情理之中
but I'm not concerned about that now.
但我现在真的不在意这些
Ijust want to do God's will.
我只想遵从上帝的意愿
And He's allowed me to go up to the mountain.
他已经允许我登上顶峰
- Jesus, I love to shoot film. - And I've looked over...
- 天啊 我喜欢拍摄 - 我放眼望下...
and I've seen...
我看到...
the promised land.
应许之地
I may not get there with you...
或许我不能陪你们走到那里
but I want you to know tonight...
但今晚 我想让你们知道
that we, as a people...
我们这个民族
will get to the promised land.
会到达应许之地
Do you feel it?.
你感觉到了吗？
X rays, is that what it is?. Does it grow hair?.
是X射线吗？会帮助长头发吗？
Is it vitamins?.
是维生素吗？
Can you feel violence?.
感觉到暴动了吗？
I don't know what to think.
我不知道该想什么
It seems like no man's life is worth anything anymore.
似乎任何人的生命都不再重要了
You see...
你看
the media's got a script now...
媒体现在有剧本了
by the numbers.
根据收视率来的
Flags at half-mast. Trips canceled.
降半旗 取消旅行
Ball games called off. Schools closed.
取消球赛 学校停课
Flags at half-mast.
降半旗
Memorial meetings. Memorial marches.
哀悼会 哀悼游行
Moments of silence.
默哀时间
A widow cries, and then she says brave words.
寡妇会哭泣 然后她说些勇敢的话
- More moments of silence... - Standing by...
- 然后继续默哀
- in our Washington studio is... - then the funeral procession.
- 现在在华盛顿演播室的是... - 然后是葬礼
a foremost expert on urban violence on the contemporary scene.
... 研究城市暴力的专家
A lot of experts...
许多专家...
saying how sick our society is, how sick we all are.
说我们的社会多么病态 我们多么病态
The script is a national drain-off.
剧本就是全国哀悼
People say, "Yeah, yeah, we're guilty. We're bad."
人们会说 “是啊 我们有罪 我们是坏人”
'Cause a lot of people are afraid. They're afraid...
因为很多人都很害怕
the Negroes are going to tear up their stores, burn neighborhoods...
他们害怕黑人拆了他们的商店 烧毁街区
so they have this nationwide...
所以他们才在全国范围...
coast-to-coast network special called "Mourn the Martyr."
从东海岸到西海岸 电视台都在播放“悼念烈士”的特辑
Nobody's really on the hook, you see?.
其实没人真正在意
Traditionally, religion has supplied the moral backstop.
传统上来说 宗教信仰提供了道德上的阻力
When the script is finished and Tuesday comes around...
剧本播完之后 到了礼拜二...
or Saturday and...
或者礼拜六...
National Drain-Off Week is over...
全国哀悼周结束了
everybody goes pretty much back to normal.
大家都恢复到正常生活
Normal this, normal that.
正常地做这个 做那个
You know, normal.
你知道的 正常生活
We will be able to speed up that day...
我们可以加快那一天的到来
when all ofGod's children--
当上帝所有的孩子们
black men and white men...
黑人和白人
Jews and gentiles...
犹太人与非犹太人
Protestants and Catholics--
新教徒与天主教徒
will be able to join hands...
能手拉着手
and sing in the words ofthe old Negro spiritual--
共同歌唱古老的黑人灵歌
Free at last! Free at last!
终于自由了！终于自由了！
Thank God Almighty, we are free at last!
感谢全能的上帝 我们终于自由了！
Goose bumps.
这让我起鸡皮疙瘩
It reminds me of church down home...
它让我想起以前家乡的教堂...
sitting there with Clovis...
我和克洛维斯...
and Grandma and Buddy.
祖母 还有巴迪坐在一起
This program, the third ofa series...
本节目 这一系列的第三集
was brought to you as a public service by station WHJP.
作为公共栏目 由WHJP电视台为您呈现
Stay tuned for the Late Show next on Channel 8.
接下来是8频道午夜秀 请锁定收看
I know your husband can't come charging through the door.
我知道你老公不可能突然冲进大门
It'd be too corny, like the Late Show.
那就太俗了 跟午夜秀一样
Buddy's dead.
巴迪已经死了
UnitedAirlines says, "Come fly with me. "
美联航说 “和我们一起飞吧”
We make it easy foryou to dojust that...
我们让旅行变得更容易
with Discover America Fare for vacation people.
“发现美国”卡 适宜经常旅行人士
And foryoung people, we have a great family plan...
给年轻人 我们有家庭套餐
for families of all ages and all sizes.
适合不同年龄组成和大小的家庭
- Well... - So the next time...
- 那... - 所以下次...
you andyour family plan a vacation...
你和家人计划出行时...
it's raining like hell, and I'm riding the C.T.A. these days.
外面倾盆大雨 而且最近我都搭地铁
- 1 :00's the last one. - rememberto fly...
- 末班车是一点钟
- the friendly skies ofUnited. - Well, thanks.
- 请记住 使用美联航 - 谢了
It's 1 1:30 on WHJP.
WHJP准点报时 现在是11点半
Harold must have me on his list.
哈洛肯定把我放入黑名单了
No, you're wrong.
没有 不会的
Once he speaks his mind, he's clear.
一旦他讲出自己的想法 他就没事了
Tonight Channel 8 proudly presents Brigitte Bardot...
今晚 8套为您呈现
- Wait! - andJack Palance...
-等一下！ - 碧姬·芭铎与杰克·帕兰斯主演
in a film by the controversial French director,Jean-L uc Godard.
极具争议的法国导演 让-吕克·戈达尔 的作品
In a moment, Contempt.
稍后开始 《蔑视》
Here.
船上
Don't want you to get wet.
我不想你被淋湿
I won't.
不会的
Come on, boy. Listen.
过来 孩子 听着
You know...
你知道吗
there's a lot of things that you don't understand about womenfolks...
关于女人 你有很多事情不了解
I want to talk to you about it, ya hear?.
我想和你聊聊这些 你在听吗
A man has got to be boss of his home.
男人要成为家里的顶梁柱
There ain't no two bosses in the family because it ain't right.
家里不能有两个顶梁柱 那就不对了
- You understand that?. - Yeah.
- 明白吗？ - 嗯
The thing I'm trying to show you is that women don't understand a man.
我要告诉你的是 女人往往不理解男人
Your home is your castle.
家是你的城堡
I don't care how bad orwhere you live or what it is.
我不管住在哪里 或者住得多差
That's your castle, and that woman was made foryou and belongs to you.
那都是你的城堡 里面的女人为你而存在 是属于你的
You don't belong to her, but she belongs to you.
你不属于她 但她属于你
You twain become one flesh, and that flesh is you.
你们俩成为一体 那一体就是你
She belongs to you, you understand?.
她是属于你的 你明白吗？
There's a lot of good womenfolks in the world, don't get me wrong.
这世上有很多好女人 不要理解错了意思
I mean, the majority of them, they get high ideas...
我是说 大部分女人 有更高的追求
Iike they want to go out on their own.
比如她们想出去独自闯荡
They want to take over things.
想自己负起责任
- That's right. Yeah. - Is that what you mean?.
- 没错 是这样 - 你是这个意思吗？
But don't you never let them, son.
但永远不要让她们这么做 儿子
Come here.
过来
- Wow! Somebody made this. - You see it?.
- 哇 这是有人弄成这样的吗 - 看到没？
Yeah, I made it. Look at this.
是的 是我弄的 看看这里
Wow!
哇
That's a shower. You take your clothes off over here...
这是个淋浴间 你把衣服脱在这
then you jump in there.
然后再进去
What'd your daddy do in West Virginia?.
你爸在西弗吉尼亚是做什么的？
Coal miner.
煤矿工人
Why isn't he coal mining now?.
那为什么现在不做了
Coal mine shut down, I reckon.
我想 是煤矿关了吧
We moved to Chicago.
我们搬到了芝加哥
He left, and we ain't seen him since.
然后他走了 我们就再也没见过他
Just took off. I don't know.
就这么走了 我也不知道
We'll be good friends, okay?.
我们会是好朋友的 好吗
Bye.
再见
Hey, champ. How you doing?.
嘿 小冠军 你好吗？
You see, the object of this one...
你看 这种练习的目标是
is speed and power...
速度和力量
so...
所以
you work on both.
这两项都要练
You see...
看到没
really, the object is...
真正的目标是
to knock the other guy's brains out, and then you win.
打爆别人的脑袋 你就赢了
Roll numberthree, numberthree. Sound roll numberthree.
三号胶卷 三号 声音来自三号胶卷
National Democratic Convention, August 1968.
全国民主党大会 1968年8月
Hey, how goes my boy, Johnny the Greek?.
嘿 我的朋友怎么样了 猛男约翰尼？
- All ri ght. Good. - Good, good.
- 挺好的 - 那就好
You look like you're doing all right these days.
你看上去这几天过得不错
I saw you in the film with Norman Mailer.
我在这片子里看到你和诺曼·梅勒在一起
- What kind of a guy is he?. - He's out of sight.
- 他是怎样一个人？- 我忘记了
I mean, Mailer is wild. He's crazy.
我是说 梅勒很狂野 是个疯子
But the thing about Mailer is that he cuts through the bullshit.
但梅勒的特点是 他不废话
I mean, Mailer is a force. He's a heavyweight.
他是一股力量 非常有影响力
Excuse me. May I make up your room, please?.
打扰了 请问我能打扫房间吗
Sure.
当然
Listen, you don't have to start until Thursday.
你礼拜四前都不必开工
- Can you get your own equipment?. - Yeah, sure.
- 能带上自己的设备吗？- 当然
- We shooting EF?. - Yeah, but not pushed.
- 我们要拍大会和游行？- 是 但不是强制的
Excuse me. I'll just change the towels...
不好意思 我就换一下毛巾
and then I won't disturb you anymore.
不做过多打扰了
You seem kind of down,John.
你看上去有点失落 约翰
Sometimes up, sometimes down.
有时候振奋 有时候失落嘛
Nah, I'm okay. I'm just anxious to get working.
我没事 只是有点担心这个工作
The photography is not the problem with this job, baby.
摄影不是这次工作的难点
This job is keeping up without being crushed...
这次的重点是 在机器不被人压坏
or having your clothes torn off.
或者衣服不被人撕碎的情况下 继续拍
You'll see the day after tomorrow.
后天你就明白了
You still see the nurse?.
你还在和那个护士约会？
No, not for some time now.
没 分手一阵子了
- What was her name?. - Ruth.
- 她叫什么名字？ - 露丝
And her number?.
她电话你有吗？
Testing station two. One, two, three, four.
测试2号机位 1 2 3 4...
Station two is good.
2号机位合格
Let's go on to station three.
继续测试3号机位
One, two, three. One, two, three. L et me see station three.
1 2 3 1 2 3 让我看看3号机位
Station three. L et me see your light up there.
3号机位 灯打开让我看看
L et's see your light up there, station three. That's good.
亮灯看看 3号机位 很好
One, two, three. One, two, three. L et me see station three.
1 2 3 1 2 3 让我看看3号机位
Station three. L et me see your light up there.
3号机位 亮灯看看
I used to come here for the circus when I was a kid.
我小时候来这里看过马戏
I can still smell it.
仍能闻到马戏团的味道
That's the stockyards.
那里是动物围栏
America is wonderful.
美国棒极了
Wonderful, wonderful, wonderful, wonderful, wonderful--
棒极了 棒极了 棒极了...
- It really makes it-- - Free
- 这才是真正的... - 自由
Who's that?.
那是谁？
Oh, wow!
噢 哇
- Y eah, man. - What's happening, man?.
- 是啊 - 怎么了 老兄？
Flashing. Flashing. Flashing, man.
闪光 闪光
- Flashing, man. Crazy, man. - The sky is blue.
- 闪光 伙计 太疯狂了 - 天是蓝色的
Out of sight, yeah.
大脑一片空白
Listen, are you hung up?.
你是不是上瘾了？
- A little strung out, mate?. - I can't understand.
- 嗑药嗑得嗨了？ - 我听不懂
Out of sight, yeah. Listen, are you hung up?.
大脑空白了 你是不是嗨了？
Hi, boys and girls. I'm Jimmy Carl Black.
大家好 男孩女孩们 我是吉米·卡尔·布莱克
I'm the Indian of the group.
我是乐队中的印第安人
What's there to live for
#还有什么值得活着#
Who needs the Peace Corps
#谁需要和平部队#
I'm completely stoned I'm hippie, and I'm trippy
#我完全醉了 我是嬉皮士 我吃迷幻药#
And a gypsy on my own
#我是自己的吉普赛#
I'll stay a week and get the grass and take a bus back home
#我会呆一个礼拜 抓螃蟹 然后坐车回家#
I'm reallyjust a phony
#我真的只是个骗子#
But forgive me 'cause I'm stoned
#但请原谅我 因为我嗨了#
Every town must have a place where phony hippies meet
#每个城镇都应该有骗子嬉皮士的聚集地#
Psychedelic dungeons
#迷幻的地牢#
Popping up on every street
#出现在每条街#
Go to
#出发#
San Francisco
#去旧金山#
How I love ya, how I love ya
#我如此爱你 我如此爱你#
Frisco
#旧金山#
Oh, my hair is getting good in the back
#噢 我的头发从后面看真好看#
Every town must have a place where phony hippies meet
#每个城镇都应该有骗子嬉皮士的聚集地#
Psychedelic dungeons
#迷幻的地牢#
Popping up on every street
#出现在每条街#
Go to
#出发#
San Francisco
#去旧金山#
First I'll buy some beads
#首先我会买些珠子#
And then perhaps a leather band to go around my head
#然后可能买个皮圈套在头上#
Some feathers and bells
#有羽毛和铃铛#
And a book oflndian lore
#一本印第安传说的书#
I will ask the chamber of commerce how to get to Haight Street
#我会问商会 怎么去嬉皮街#
And smoke an awful lot ofdope
#抽许多大麻#
I will wander around barefoot
#我会赤脚游荡#
I will have a psychedelic gleam in my eye at all times
#眼前一直出现虚幻的闪光#
I will love everyone I will love the police
#我会爱每个人 我会爱警察#
As they kick the shit out ofme on the street
#当他们在街上暴打我的时候#
I can't. Harold's in there. Please don't.
不行 哈洛在里面 别这样
Don't. Please.
求你 别这样
Harold, you up here?.
哈洛 你在上面吗？
I asked his friends. I told you...
我问过他的朋友了 我跟你说...
I asked everybody in the whole neighborhood.
我问了这个居民区所有的人
I've been up all night long looking for him.
我整晚没睡 都在找他
Please, please, can't you send somebody to help me find him?.
求你了 不能叫人来帮我一起找他吗
- You people-- - Hello?.
- 你们这些人... - 喂？
Look, lady, we can't help. The city's been invaded.
女士 我们帮不了你 这城市已经暴动了
I can't spare a man.
我们人手不够
They usually come back, lady.
孩子通常都会自己回来的
Ladies and gentlemen!
女士们 先生们
My name is Harold Horton!
我叫哈洛·霍顿
This is Harold Horton!
我是哈洛·霍顿
Hawaii votes 26 votesyes.
夏威夷有26票支持
Idaho, 25.
爱达荷州 共25票
Idaho casts 22 1/2 votesyes...
其中有22票半支持
2 1/2 votes no.
两票半反对
Iowa passes for the time being.
爱荷华州暂时通过
Iowa passes. Kansas, 38.
爱荷华州通过 堪萨斯州 38票
Kansas casts 38 votesyes.
堪萨斯州38票赞成
Kentucky, 46.
肯塔基州 46票
Ifyou do not leave, I will orderyour arrest.
如果你们还不走 我要把你们抓起来了
L eave the park at once.
马上离开公园
You are in violation ofthe law.
你们已经触犯了法律
Hell, no, we won't go!
绝不 我们绝不走！
Peace! Now!
我们要和平！
I'm looking for John Katselas.
我找约翰·卡塞拉斯
Yes. Yes. Where is he?.
是的 是的 他在哪？
Do you have the phone number?.
你有他电话吗？
Where is the amphitheater?.
露天剧场在哪？
Peace! Now! Peace! Now!
我们要和平！我们要和平！
Join us!Join us!Join us!
加入我们！加入我们！
Move out. Move out, man.
出来 出来 大伙
- Come on, now. - Michigan and 1 8th.
- 来吧 - 密歇根大街和18街有暴乱
Join us!Join us!Join us!
加入我们！加入我们！
Retreat! Retreat! Everybody retreat!
撤退 撤退 所有人撤退
This way! State Street! State Street!
这边走 州立大街 州立大街
Stay together! Don't panic!
呆在一起 不要慌张
Let's go!
我们走
Everybody, move out!
所有人 出来
Move it! Move it! Where's the secondary?.
快走 第二队在哪？
Stay together! Stay together!
呆在一起 呆在一起
We can't get beat ifwe stay together!
呆在一起就不会被打败！
Don't panic!
不要慌张！
- Over to the right! - Sit down!
- 靠右 - 坐下
Drop down! Get down!
坐下 坐下
Back up and sit down!
往后退 坐下
The whole world is watching!
全世界都在看 全世界都在看
All right, you guys, move!
好了 你们这群人 走开
Remember Prague! Remember Czechoslovakia!
牢记布拉格 牢记捷克斯洛伐克
Don't forget Budapest!
不要忘记布达佩斯！
Get those cameras out of here!
叫摄像的走开！
NBC, come back!
NBC的人 回来
Stay with us!
跟我们呆在一起
NBC! Hey! Come back!
NBC的 嘿！回来
All right, people. Let's keep our cool.
好了 大家 让我们保持冷静
There's nothing to fear ofthese people. Keep our cool.
跟他们没有什么好说的 保持冷静
Yeah, tanks. It's incredible.
坦克啊 真了不起
They're stopping them on 1 8th.
他们在18街进行拦截
Reinforce that lock.
加强那道锁
Don't turn your backs to them.
不要背对他们
Watch those two. Just move ahead.
注意那两个人 往前开
Move right ahead.
一直往前开
That's it. Turn left. Turn right. Turn right.
行了 右转 右转
Reinforce the single line.
守住这条路线
You are subject to arrest.
你们都要被逮捕
Fuck you, pig!
操你妈的 蠢猪
You are in violation ofthe law.
你们触犯了法律
You are subject to arrest.
应当被逮捕
We have information for the persons amongyou...
我们有消息说 你们当中的一些人
who may attempt to injure police officers.
试图袭警
We will take all necessary precautions...
我们会采取一切必要措施
- to protect the policemen. - Fuck you!
- 保护警察 - 操你妈的！
This is the final warning. L eave now.
最后一次警告 现在马上离开
Look out, Haskell! It's real!
当心 哈斯克尔 这是来真的了！
The mayor of Chicago.
... 任命为芝加哥市长
Everybody gather in the center ofthe park.
大家聚集到公园中间去
Don't struggle with them. Just hold hands.
不要跟他们争执 我们握起手来
Pigs!
猪头
Get the badge numbers!
记下警徽号码！
Pigs are whores! Pigs are whores!
蠢猪！贱人！蠢猪！贱人！
Get up and get off!
起来 滚开
Let's get out of here, you son of a bitch!
我们走吧 你们这些狗娘养的
Move!
快走！
You stinkin' Commies!
恶心的共党！
Pigs!
蠢猪！
Go home, pigs!
回家去 蠢猪！
Go home, you fuckin' cops!
滚回家去 该死的警察！
Mr. Chairman, Colorado rises...
主席先生 现在科罗拉多州的事件
to a point ofinformation.
成为新闻焦点
Is there any rule under which Mayor Daley can be compelled...
有没有市长能强行执行的规定
to suspend the police state terror perpetrated this minute...
来阻止州警在希尔顿酒店门口
on kids in front of the Conrad Hilton?
对孩子们实施的恐怖犯罪行为？
The--
这...
Mr. Chairman.
主席先生
The chair must announce...
主席团必须宣布
that we are calling the roll ofthe States...
我们正在号召国家的改革
and we recognize...
而且我们意识到
delegates for no otherpurpose than to answer the call.
除了相应此号召 我们没有其他任何目的
Pigs eat shit! Pigs eat shit!
猪都去吃屎！猪都去吃屎！
Pi gs are whores! Pi gs are whores!
猪都是贱人！猪都是贱人！
Ifyou don 't move up on the parkway, I'll orderyour arrest.
如果你们再不去到道路上 我们就要逮捕了
Move up on the parkway or I must orderyour arrest.
马上去道路上 不然要逮捕你们
There isn 't any distinction anymore for us.
我们不会再区别对待
You go up on the side ofthe fire structure, we're gonna get you.
你们越过警戒线的话 就会被逮捕
You come off on our side, then you get out. You dig?
你们越界的话 也得滚 知道吗？
I got a message now from the drop-off community.
我们刚收到一条来自大会的消息
There are people in the streets all over this country.
全国上下都有人们上街游行
Up against the wall, motherfuckers!
动真格的了 混蛋们
Will the sergeant at arms enforce order in the convention?
武装军队会执行大会的命令吗
The question is on the motion.
这问题正在提议中
So many as in favor, vote aye.
很多人都表示赞同 投票支持
- Aye!
- 支持 - 支持！
Those opposed, no. They ayes have it.
反对者投反对票
Sieg heil! Sieg heil!
元首万岁！（纳粹礼）
No more war! No more war!
停止战争！停止战争！
Join us! Join us! Join us!
加入我们！加入我们！
Mama!
妈妈
Ma!
妈
A friend ofmine from El Paso was with me.
我和一个来自德州艾尔帕索的朋友在一起
Somebody threw something. He said, "Didyou see that?
有人扔了什么东西 他问 “你看到没？”
It was a cap or something. " I said, "No. "
是个帽子之类的 我说没有
Some cop says, "What'dyou throw? What are you doing here?"
有个警察说“你扔了什么？你们在这干嘛？”
He said, "I'm from El Paso, Texas. " Then he pushed him into the crowd.
他说 “我是德州艾尔帕索来的” 然后警察把他推进了人群里
They're trying to keep them contained...
警察想把它们包围住
so they can beat them up later.
我猜之后警察就能把他们揍一顿
- That's right. - Then this girl passed through--
- 没错 - 然后有个女孩经过
The policemen are grabbing and beating everybody in sight.
警察抓住眼前所有的人暴打
A line ofpolicemen has cut off the very front ofthe Hilton.
一排警察堵在希尔顿酒店门口
- There's mayhem in the streets. - The victim was identified...
- 街上一片混乱 - 受害者被确认为
as former Channel 8 News cameraman,John Katselas.
前8频道摄影师 约翰·卡塞拉斯
Katselas was taken to Michael Reese Hospital...
卡塞拉斯被送往迈克尔瑞斯医院
where he's reported to be in critical condition.
据医院消息 他情况危急
Cause ofthe accident is under investigation.
事故起因还在调查中
A woman companion, not yet identified, was dead on arrival.
和他同行的女士 身份还未确认 救援到达时已经死亡
People were being clubbed--
人们被棍子暴打...
and I mean in Technicolor 3-D--
我是说 在彩色 3D画面下
and they were crying and screaming.
他们在哭喊 尖叫
I don 't know that I've seen any bloodyet...
我不知道自己有没有看到流血
but I've seen some liquid on the ground.
但我看到地上有一些液体
People were standing around crying.
人们四处站着 哭喊
What's your reaction to this girl with the McCarthy pin?
关于那个戴着麦卡锡胸针的女孩 你怎么看？
I have no comment.
无可奉告
Girls, girls, boys, people of every description are being grabbed...
女孩 男孩 各种各样的人都被抓起来
and dragged into paddy wagons.
被拖进警车
What didyou say?
你怎么说？
And they're chasing people, particularly people...
他们还在追一些人
with anarchist flags or anything like that.
尤其是那些拿着无政府主义旗帜之类的人
You can see crowds running in all directions...
你们能看到人群朝各个方向奔逃
and plenty ofthings are being thrown.
很多东西被扔来扔去
Police have just grabbed somebody...
警察只是抓到一个人
and are beating him over the head.
就朝他头上暴打
The whole crowd across the street isyelling, "Sieg heil."
整个街上的人都在喊 “元首万岁”
Another melee is taking place in the park...
还有一处混乱的场面是在公园
right in front ofthe nation.
就在整个国家面前
Right in front ofthe entire nation, this is happening.
就在整个国家面前 发生了这一切
NBC- TV is on the roof of the Haymarket Cocktails/Restaurant--
NBC电视台的人在海马基特餐厅顶楼
part ofthe Statler Hilton--
属于希尔顿酒店的
seeing these people being dragged into the police wagon.
看着这些人被抓进警车
The whole world is watching!
全世界都在看着！全世界都在看着！
I'm a successful businessman. I've been saying, like everybody else...
我是个成功的商人 我一直跟其他人意见相同
"These kids are a bunch ofbums. "
“这些孩子只是群流浪者”
Then I finally found out when I got down here...
来了这里之后 我终于发现
that, goddamn it, the kids are right.
真该死 这些孩子是对的
- What made you find out? - I got gassed.
- 你是怎么发现的？- 我被毒气熏了
I came down here, and I got gassed.
我来这里 结果被毒气熏了
Andyou kids, go, man, go!
孩子们说 快走 先生 快走
The police just grabbed somebody...
警察只是抓了谁
and are beating him over the head...
就把他暴打一顿
and are trying to throw him...
而且想把他们
into the paddy wagon.
抓进警车
A scoop, made ofpolice, simply...
一个警察制造的独家新闻
flies out and-- flies out--
就这样传出来...
Move! Move!
走 快走
I'm being made to move.
我被逼着往前走
The cameraman, everybody's being made to move now.
摄像师 所有人都被逼着往前走
Move! Move! Everybody move!
走！所有人都往前走！
We're being thrown up against the wall.
我们被逼得走投无路
Let's go!
快走！
Ijust got out ofbeing smashed against the wall...
我差点被扔到墙壁上
by the skin ofmy teeth...
差点撞碎牙齿
by showing my press badge to a kindly policeman.
还好给警察出示了我的记者证
People are being smashed up against the wall...
人们都被扔到墙上
and are being hit...
遭到警察们棍棒的
by the police with their clubs.
毒打
And those are real night sticks...
那些都是真正的警棍
and people are really being hit.
人们真的是被暴打